DR. WHO: In this
video, we're going
to discuss some aspects
of the biology of cancer.
So imagine this epithelial
tissue before you.
There's a single cell that
acquires mutations, possibly
in genes that
regulate cell growth.
And as these
mutations accumulate,
the cell starts to proliferate.
It loses its anchoring
to its surroundings
and starts to
multiply as a tumor.
As it grows, it produces
some growth factors
that allow small blood
vessels to invade the tumor
and to provide it
with nutrients.
And this process is
called "angiogenesis."
As the tumor continues to
grow, sometimes the tumor
will invade surrounding
tissues, or it
might be able to cross
into either a blood vessel
or perhaps into a lymphatic.
And by doing so, it can spread,
and this process of spreading
is known as "metastasis."
So by metastasis
through the blood,
a tumor might
reach other organs.
So you could have secondaries
of a tumor in the liver,
or in the kidney, or
the lungs, for instance,
or even in the brain.
And sometimes the tumor will
spread through lymphatics
to the draining
lymph node, and one
can see an enlargement
of lymph nodes
in the vicinity of the tumor.
Now as tumors grow, they are
sustained by many things.
One is you have the sustained
proliferative signaling.
You have actually the
absence of cell death,
so tumors might shut off
the process of apoptosis.
They may evade
mechanisms of suppressing
cell growth mediated by genes
known as "tumor suppressors."
And these cells also acquire
the ability to metastasize
and have angiogenesis.
Now in the old days,
'til about 15 years
ago, the general
view of tumor genesis
was that it involved these
properties that basically
affected the growth of the
cell and its migration,
and the immune system was
not brought into the picture.
So one goes back and
looks at classical reviews
by Doug Hanahan
and Bob Weinberg.
They describe certain
properties of tumors,
and they call these the six
hallmarks of cancer, which
include evasion of
growth suppressors,
the activation of
invasion and metastasis,
the enabling of
replicative immortality,
the induction of angiogenesis,
the resisting of cell death,
and sustaining
proliferative signaling.
But it was recognized, and it
had been recognized before,
that sometimes
tumors seem to grow
in the context of inflammation.
And it's also been recognized
that sometimes when
tumors are infiltrated
by immune cells,
they have a better prognosis.
So we do know that tumors are
infiltrated by immune cells,
and that sometimes it is
the inflammatory cells which
provide mutagens and drive
the growth of the tumor
by creating more mutations.
So in this situation, you can
think of inflammatory cells
being pro-tumorigenic.
But then there are many other
contexts in which immune cells
come into the tumor.
Sometimes they would have
eliminated the tumor,
but we wouldn't have
seen it, and that's
called "immune surveillance."
But on other occasions,
the immune cells
are induced to become
exhausted, and effete,
and then the tumor grows.
So today, when we think about
the cardinal signs of cancer
we include among these
cardinal features of cancer
a few aspects of the
interaction of the immune system
with the tumor.
So on the one
hand, the tumor has
survived because it has
acquired the ability
to avoid immune destruction.
On the other hand,
sometimes the tumor
has grown because immune cells
have created the environment
for the growth of the tumor.
So when you think of
the biology of cancer,
we now think of the
biology of cancer
as including aspects
controlling cell growth,
angiogenesis,
metastasis, but also we
think about the interplay
between the immune system
and the tumor, which could
work in two directions.
The immune system could
have induced the tumor,
but the immune system
also has the power
to help us get rid of the tumor.